ERIC G. HAGER

1600 15th St. San Francisco, CA 94115

Phone: (646) 531-6182 • Email: enic@isabel.io

Professional Summary

Eric is an agricultural and technology entrepreneur, systems designer, co-founder & CEO of leabel Technologies. He focuse s primarily on the design of innovative crop intensification systems and companion digital technologies. Over the past several years he has designed, managed and implemented agricultural and technology products and programs across three continents for some of the world's largest NGO's including the World Food Program's Innovation Accelerator and the International Institute of Tropical Agriculture.

Business Development & Technology Consulting

UNITED NATIONS WORLD FOOD PROGRAM

(Mar. 2016 - Present)

- Currently, leading the development of H2Grow, the World Food Program's online platform for capacity-building in hydroponics
- Developed hydroponic systems for the production of fresh animal feed in the desert in partnership with the WFP-Algeria and WFP-Chad
- Assisted WFP staff with the deployment of over 100 hydroponic systems in Algeria and Chad
- Manage d the official launch of "Hydro App" with local governments in Lima, Los Olivos and Ventanilla in Peru
- Led a team of developers for "HydroApp" the United Nations World Food Program's primary hydroponics mobile application
- Led a UN-sponsored team to introduce the pilot program for "HydroApp" in the rural outskirts of Lima, Peru to initiate a minimum viable product via WhatsApp to validate use-cases for application features

INTERNATIONAL INSTITUTE OF TROPICAL AGRICULTURE

(Oct 2017 - Jan 2018)

Developed off-grid cultivation and remote monitoring systems for production of African yarn seed BCI - SOLAR

(Feb. 2016 - May 2016)

- Developed cash-flow models, financial and cost projections for a steel plant manufacturing for solar tracking systems
- Produced detailed comparable analysis to determine optimal location for producing steel tubes in Arizona, California
- Conducted extensive research on manufacturing incentive packages throughout the Western United States
- Created detailed state-by-state research reports on manufacturing incentive packages and local regulatory schemes

Start-ups

ISABEL TECHNOLOGIES INC.

(May 2015 - Present)

San Francisco, CA

Co-Founder & Director of Operations

- Established a Nigerian subsidy and secured financing from a Nigerian angel investor.
- Established key partnerships with the World Food Program and the International Institute of Tropic al Agriculture. Initiated key partnerships with the San Francisco City Government & the Treasure Island Homeless Development
- Initiative to secure lease-free space for Isabel's research greenhouse, the first of its kind within the city limits
- Developed training program for new employees focusing on cutting-edge hydroponic farming techniques, system
- maintenance and the fundamentals of on-farm food safety
- Led our product development team to enhance greenhouse automation, farm management and food traceability applications
- Worked directly with international and local vendors to source greenhouse and hydroponic systems
- Raise d \$250,000 in seed capital from, Sheridan-Dose Investments

FARM-X

(May 2013 - Aug. 2015)

Berkeley, CA

- Co-founder
- Social venture seeking to create a career pipeline to indoor farming and related fields for at-risk youth in the Bay area Selected for Earth Island Institute Project Support Program, a leading incubator for start-up environmental nonprofit projects
- Awarded Northern California Environmental Grassroots grant from the Rose Foundation for Communities and the Environment
- Raise d funding from the Oakland Unified School District and the Rose Foundation to launch a STEM/vocational training
- program at Castlemont High School in East Ouldand Facilitated a student-led conversion of a former JROTC gun range into a vertical hydroponic greenhouse
- Selected to exhibit Farm-X at the Italian Pavillion of the 15th? International Architecture Biennale located in Venice, Italy Partnered with the University of Bologna's Agronomy Department on a 6-month long feasibility study for vertical farm designs
- LIFECYCLE GARDENS (Sept. 2012 - Jun. 2013)

Product Manager

South Rosa, CA

- Life Cycle Gardens is an environmentally conscious brand seeking to provide all people with a renewable source of fresh
- produce that can be grown a thome; regardless of space or sunlight restrictions
- Developed sales, marketing and positioning strategy for LifeCycle Garden's first product, Garden-on-Wheelz
- Headed product development and implemented new product features such as Gurden-on-Whee le's innovative self-watering system.

Awards & Other

Awards

- Singularity Global Impact Challenge Finalist
- World Food Program Innovation Ac celerator Bootcamp Spring 2017 Cohort

Certifications and Skills

- Financial Modeling & Valuation, Grant Writing, Product Design, Invision, Sketch, Android Studio, Sketchup Pro & Layout,
- Professional working proficiency in Spanish
- Certified ServeSafe Food Protection Manager

Volunteer Experience and Interests

- Volunteer English Teacher in Nepal
- Avid traveler including over 25 countries and counting

(Apr. 2012 - August 2012)

Education

UNIVERSITY OF SAN FRANCISCO

Class of 2018

Backelor of Arts in Economics, College of Arts & Sciences

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

UNITED STATES GOVERNMENT | Washington D.C. | Sept. 2018 – Present

Executive Director, Login.gov (US Digital Identity Project)

Head of a national program to provide a single solution for digital access to all government services

Lead a team of 30+ FTEs across development, financing, and product

Developed the business model and oversaw launch of pay-for-service model

UNITED STATES GOVERNMENT | Washington D.C. | Oct. 2017 - Present

Presidential Innovation Fellow, Veterans Affairs

Redesigning backend data architecture modernization strategy for the VA

Aligning innovation efforts across the VA, including portfolio creation and prioritization

Member of GSA/TTS steering group to better align 18F, OPP, and PIF teams

BIONIC | New York, NY | Feb. 2016 – Oct. 2017

Vice President, Head of Product & Entrepreneur in Residence

Built startups from ideation through testing, modeling, and launch with F100 companies

Oversaw all internal products, including CX/UX design, development, and client partnerships

Partners: Nike, Citibank, Exelon, Proctor & Gamble, AB Inbev, General Electric

ISABEL | San Francisco, CA & Abuja, Nigeria | Nov. 2015 – Present

Co-Founder

Raised initial capital for seed-funded, SF-based urban ag-tech startup (Isabel.io)

Focus on sustainable farming and agriculture ecosystems from seed to market

Currently operating in Africa, Latin America, and the USA

LAUNCHPAD CENTRAL | San Francisco, CA | May 2015 – Jan. 2016

Vice President, Operations

Head of operations, marketing, client delivery and corporate strategy

Worked directly on core strategy for Steve Blank founded startup

Developed services to promote innovation in large organizations, incl: Mayo Clinic, NSF, NIH

JOHN WILEY & SONS | New York, NY & Oxford, UK | Jan. 2013 - May 2015

Managing Director & Global Head of Technology Design & Innovation

Built & managed \$3.5M/yr experience research, design and innovation program (IDEA LAB)

Hired 25+ team and developed global idea management platform, speaker series, workshops

Extensive presentation activity with executive leadership and internal / external stakeholders

CITY FARM FISH | Brooklyn, NY | Sept. 2011 - June 2015

Co-Founder

Head of environmentally, socially, and economically sustainable aquaponic project (cityfarmfish.com) Managed community outreach, business dev, design, sourcing, and 12+ global/regional partnerships Winner, Pratt Sustainability Incubator inclusion program

RELX GROUP (LEXIS NEXIS) | New York, NY & Sydney, AU | Oct. 2008 – Jan. 2013

Senior Director, Global Product Strategy

Invented and developed highly successful Microsoft partnership product (\$100M+)

Directed requirements, dev, CX, UX, and release across 50+ employees and 3 continents

Directed focus groups, 1:1s, ethnography, and usability studies touching 1,000+ users globally

Public face of new products, speaking at 25+ public and private engagements/yr worldwide

HELLER EHRMAN L.L.P. | San Francisco, CA | May 2006 – Oct. 2008

Attorney

Practiced law focused on international antitrust litigation related to software and technology Represented Microsoft in Europe

UNIVERSITY OF CALIFORNIA, BERKELEY | Berkeley, CA | Spring/Fall Semesters 2006

Graduate Student Instructor, Berkeley Law

Taught undergraduate Comparative Private Law and graduate Legal Writing while at Berkeley Law

UNITED TALENT AGENCY | Beverly Hills, CA | April 2003 - Aug. 2004

Agent (training)

Maintained client relations and assisted in negotiating contracts for "A-List" feature film artists Developed and managed UTA Production website

HBO / FILM AND TELEVISION PRODUCTION | Los Angeles, CA | Oct. 2001 – April 2003

1st Assistant Director / Writer / Coordinator / Production

Credits include over ten films and one Golden Globe winning television series (Curb Your Enthusiasm) Hired & managed crews of 100+

APPLIED COMMUNICATION / TEXT 100 | Amsterdam, NL | June 1999 - Oct. 2001

Business Communications Analyst, Public Relations

Analyzed trends and invented research methodologies for Oracle, HP, Avaya, PayPal, etc.

Opened and managed award-winning communications research branch serving EMEA

LA PROGRAMA, UNIVERSIDAD DE BUENOS AIRES | Buenos Aires, AR | Feb. 1997 – May 1998 Lecturer in English

Designed curriculum and taught intermediate and advanced level English and Humanities courses

RELEVANT & RECENT ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

- Board of Directors, **eQualit.ie** (Sept. 2016 current) leadership support for global IT security firm focused on digital protection of civil society.
- Founder Advisor, Massive.sci (Dec. 2016 current) Focused on expanding the reach and accessibility of STEM-focused media. Funded by Bloomberg, General Electric.
- Founder Advisor, Science.ai (Jan. 2016 current) Building the future publishing platform for scientific and academic research. Funded through Series A.
- Founder Advisor, ParisPicnic.com (March 2014 Dec. 2016) Innovative picnic delivery service and storefront. Voted the TripAdvisor #2 restaurant in Paris for over 12 months.

alex@dalessio.nyc +1.917.838.2062

EDUCATION

YALE UNIVERSITY | New Haven, CT

Masters in Environmental Science and Management (MEM) (expected 2020)

Focus: agriculture/renewable energy science and policy

OXFORD UNIVERSITY | Oxford, United Kingdom

Masters in Business Administration (MBA)

Honors: Distinction in Strategy, Leadership, Business Transformation, Mergers & Acquisitions

Nominated and elected Class Representative

UNIVERSITY OF CALIFORNIA, BERKELEY | Berkeley, CA

Juris Doctor (JD)

Honors: Public Interest Law Fellow (Front Line, Dublin, Ireland); Federal Public Defenders Law Fellow; Graduate Student Instructor, Comparative Private Law & Legal Writing; Judge, Moot Court Competition

UNIVERSITY OF COLORADO, BOULDER | Boulder, CO

Bachelor of Arts (BA) in Psychology; Minor, Spanish Language

Year abroad: University of Alicante, Spain

LANGUAGES & ADDITIONAL SKILLS

Languages: English (native); Spanish (excellent); Italian (proficient); Dutch (basic)
Skills: fluency in teaching and leading human centered design, design thinking, and agile/iterative design/development processes; basic knowledge of coding languages; strong office technology experience and awareness, including solution evaluation and acquisition

PATENTS

Systems And Methods For Ranking A Plurality Of Documents Based On User Activity United States 20140236964 A1 | Issued: August 24, 2014

Ranking Documents Based On User Activity

United States 2014130308 A1 | Issued: August 24, 2014

Systems And Methods For Providing A Validation Tool United States 08239415 | Issued: August 7, 2012

Systems And Methods For Creating And Using A Research Map

United States 20120166425 | Issued: June 28, 2012

INTERNATIONAL EXPERIENCE

Lived in 8 countries: USA, Fiji Islands, Spain, Argentina, The Netherlands, Italy, Ireland, and Australia

Worked professionally in 6 countries: USA, Argentina, The Netherlands, Italy, Ireland, and Australia

Traveled to 70+ countries: sailed the Amazon and the Nile; traveled the full length of the Pan-American highway and the Trans-Siberian railroad; crossed parts of East, West, and North Africa; cruised South East Asia; trekked across Northern India and the border of Pakistan; and crisscrossed Europe various times.